SIRUI ZHU

Portfolio available at : siruizhu.github.io

SELECTED PROJECTS

Treasure of architecture: China to better protect architecture relics

https://siruizhu.github.io/cultural--relics/ API to access the data. Interactive graphics showing all cultural relics names, classifications and distribution.

The past 50 years of refugees crisis

https://siruizhu.github.io/refugee project/ Exploration of 50 years refugees dataset. Python(pandas) for data cleaning and analysis, visualization using D3. Scrollytelling with interactive charts.

Hollywood Age Gap: A Visual Exploration of Age and On-Screen Romance

https://malbasi.github.io/hollywood-age-gap/ Group project: Analyse the hollywood movies age gap. Visualization using D3. Scrollytelling with interactive charts.

What is the vainest country in the world?

https://siruizhu.github.io/plastic surgery/ Exploration of plastic surgery around the world. Python and pandas for data cleaning and analysis, visualization using matplotlib and Illustrator.

What do critics think of Asian Movies?

https://siruizhu.github.io/BBC movie critics/ Interactive visualization of film ratings. Selenium and BeautifulSoup to scrape data from IMDB and Douban. Python to geocode and export GeoJSON, Leaflet and Mapbox for the final visualization.

In progress

Brazil dam disaster

Working with a coursemate on mapping the dam collapse location, and using visuals showing details of this disaster.

EDUCATION

Lede Program for Data Journalism, Columbia University

May 2018 - Dec. 2018 New York, USA (Obtained \$16,000 Scholarship) Courses: Python, data analysis with pandas, matplotlib, SQL, JavaScript, D3.js, basic machine learning (regression and prediction) and text analysis, web app development, geographic analysis with QGIS, Scrollytelling.

M.A., Broadcast Journalism, University of Sheffield

Sept. 2014 - Sept. 2015 Sheffield, UK

Portfolio: London's Chinatown Feels the Squeeze of Rent Rises (video)

B.A., Broadcasting and Compering, Wuhan University

Sept. 2010 - June 2014 Wuhan, China

Dissertation: Analysis of China Reality Show from the Perspective of Communication.

VOLUNTEER WORK

Sheffield Student Union Charity Hitchhike Mar. 2015 Wuhan Green NGO Oct. 2011 340 W 86th st # 6A New York, 10024 (646) 9449596 surizhu9@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Data: Python, pandas, matplotlib, SQL, APIs,

Selenium, BeautifulSoup

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, D3.js Mapping: Leaflet, QGIS, Mapbox Services: Github, Travis, Heroku Applications: Adobe Illustrator,

Photoshop, Adobe Premiere, Final Cut Pro,

Edius

Language: Mandarin(Native) English(Professional)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Thomson Reuters | New York, USA *Data Visualization Developer intern* April 1st 2019 to present

Wuhan Dyclub Data Technology Lit.Co. | Wuhan, China

Training Supervisor Nov. 2016 - May 2018
Organized more than twenty Dyclub data
journalism online trainings. Managed and
wrote articles on Wechat channel's special
column "Weekly Data Journalism."
Operated visualization tool Dydata.io,
executed data analysis on users.
Organized "Third Data Journalism
Competition" and award ceremony.

Hubei Televisions | Wuhan, China

TV Producer Mar 2016 - Oct. 2016 Produced children's reality show and wrote children's show script.

UK Chinese Times | London, UK

News Editor intern June 2015 - July 2015 Edited international news pieces

China National Radio | Beijing

News Editor intern Feb. 2013 - May 2013 Edited radio news, work on 2013 NPC and CPPCC reporting for two weeks.

AWARDS

Excellent Journalist of Wuhan University

June 2011

Excellent Student for University Article Writing Competition for Celebrating Xinhai Revolution 100th Anniversary

Oct. 2011